# SAI CHANG

# Senior Web Developer

EMAIL thisissaichang@gmail.com ADDRESS Lakeland, Florida, 33810

LINKEDIN https://www.linkin.com/in/sai-chang

## **SUMMARY**

As a senior full-stack web engineer (JavaScript / Python / PHP) with 8+ years of experience, I always try to produce highquality code which is testable and scalable. In the last 4 years of my career, I mainly worked on JavaScript frameworks and I built a number of websites for both startup and large enterprise-level companies focusing on adapting, and utilizing new technologies, best practices, and collaborating with teammates to achieve great results.

## **EDUCATION**

**Beacon College** Leesburg, FL Sep 2009 - Nov 2014

- Major: Computer Science, Bachelor's Degree (in-major GPA: 3.44)
- Certificate (Minor): Electrical Engineering
- Programming Courses: Algorithms & Data Structures, Operating Systems, Networks, Database

### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Create.xyz Senior Frontend Engineer

Mar 2019 - Present

- Built PWA for machine marketing SAAS platform using React, TypeScript, GraphQL, MUI and Node.js, PostgreSQL.
- Lead the front-end team, collaborated with managers & stakeholders to achieve business objectives in the application.
- Integrated Mixpanel to analyze users' activities on our platform.
- Reduced the complexity of component management by 30% using **Storybook** and managed atomic UI components in Storybook.
- Worked directly with the design team to produce pixel-perfect, responsive pages.
- Covered 60% of automation testing following TDD principle.
- Used Technologies: React, React Hook, React Native, Next.js, TypeScript, Node.js, GraphQL, MUI, Tailwind CSS, Storybook, Mixpanel, React Testing Library, Jest, Cypress, PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, AWS, Git, JIRA.

#### Webflow **Full Stack Engineer**

Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- Built and extended new feature to design extension app of Webflow platform using React, Angular, Node.js, Django.
- Built scalable APIs using Node.js and Python to fetch application record details; secured APIs through OAuth.
- Worked with high-load systems (more than 100, 000 daily users) optimizing performance and managed state using Flux.
- Maintained back-end code built using Node.js, PostgreSQL collaborated with product team to implement new features and collaborated with product team to implement new features.
- Converted Figma design into pixel-perfect and responsive pages using Styled Component and MUI.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Styled Component, Bootstrap, MUI, React, Next.js, Flux, Python, Django, Express.is, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS, Docker, Nginx, Slack, Jira, GitHub.

#### NetTech Web Developer

Feb 2015 - Aug 2017

- Worked in agile team to migrate legacy e-Commerce PHP / Laravel project to React / Node / MongoDB stack.
- Migrated old codebases with **jQuery** to **React** to improve performance.
- Translated Figma designs into responsive & pixel-perfect pages using React.
- Had peer code reviews to improve code quality and follow best practices.
- Used technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP, Laravel, React, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Figma, Docker, GitHub, Jira, Slack.

## SKILLS (YEARS OF EXPERIENCE)

- JavaScript (8) Vue.js (3)
- Python (4)
- Ruby (2)
- SCSS/SASS (3)
- Jest (5)

Cypress (3)

Docker (2)

- React (6)

- Angular (1)
- Django (2)
- Ruby on Rails (1)
  Bootstrap (4)

- React Native (2) Node.js (5)
- FastAPI (2)
- Golang (2)
- Tailwind CSS (3) AWS (2)

- Next.js (4)
- Express.js (4)
- MongoDB (3)
- PHP (5)
- MUI (3)

- TypeScript (3)
- Nest.js (1)
- GraphQL(4)
- Laravel (4)
- Chakra UI (2)
- Kubernetes (1)